<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic template="Default" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Editor Toolbar</title>
  <keywords>
    <keyword translate="true">Editor Toolbar</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Editor Toolbar</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">GExperts includes the ability to place a user-defined toolbar in the IDE code editor windows (see the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Code_Editor_Enhancements" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Code Editor</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab in the GExperts configuration dialog). &#160;To select which buttons are visible on the toolbar, drag buttons from the list of Available Buttons to the Toolbar Buttons list. &#160;Reordering buttons in the selected Buttons list is also possible using drag-and-drop or the Up and Down arrows. To remove a button from the toolbar, you can drag it from the Toolbar Buttons list and drop it back onto the Available Buttons list </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The majority of the available buttons are taken from IDE&apos;s main menu, but there are also several special buttons in the GExperts category that perform custom actions. &#160;These custom actions can execute GExperts experts, execute editor experts, show a list dropdown list of forms or units in the current project, or allow you to select a component on the current form by class and name. &#160;There is also a button to jump to specific positions in the current Delphi unit. &#160;An example editor toolbar is shown here behind the toolbar configuration dialog:</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="Configuration Editor Toolbar.png" scale="100.00%" style="font-family:&apos;MS Sans Serif&apos;; font-size:8pt; color:#000000;"></image></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Note:</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> Vertical toolbars do not support button separators.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
